{
  "1": {
    "path": "tictactoe",
    "credit": "Forkk.net",
    "creditlink": "http://www.forkk.net",
    "next": "PUZZLE/2",
    "name": "Tic Tac Toe",
    "name_pt": "Jogo da Velha"
  },
  "2": {
    "question": "Your socks drawer contains 10 pairs of white socks and 10 pairs of black socks. Suppose you are in the dark and need to get one sock at a time, without knowing which one. How many socks do you need to get until you have a pair with matching color?",
    "question_pt": "Sua gaveta de meias contém 10 pares de meias brancas e 10 pares de meias pretas. Suponha que você só possa pegar uma meia de cada vez e que você não possa ver a cor desta meia até que a retire da gaveta, quantas meias você terá que pegar até obter, no mínimo, um par de meias da mesma cor?",
    "answer": "3",
    "answer_pt": "3",
    "note": "Please answer using numeric digits.",
    "note_pt": "Responda usando números (dígitos).",
    "percent": false,
    "credit": "RachaCuca",
    "creditlink": "http://rachacuca.com.br",
    "next": "PUZZLE/3",
    "name": "Messy Drawer",
    "name_pt": "Gaveta Bagunçada"
  },
  "3": {
    "question": "What is the name of the volcanö who erupted in 2010 and shut down much of Europe's airspace?",
    "question_pt": "Qual o nome do vulcãö que entrou em erupção em 2010 e provocou um caos aéreo na Europa?",
    "answer": "Eyjafjallajökull",
    "answer_pt": "Eyjafjallajökull",
    "percent": false,
    "credit": false,
    "next": "PUZZLE/4"
  },
  "4": {
    "question": "What are the 2 numbers whose product is 48 and, when the higher number is divided for the lower, the result is 3?",
    "question_pt": "Quais são os 2 números cujo produto é 48 e, quando o número maior é dividido pelo menor, obtem-se quociente 3?",
    "answer": "12, 4",
    "answer_pt": "12, 4",
    "note": "Separate the answer using commas. E.g.: 'X, Y' (X is the higher number, Y is the lower number)",
    "note_pt": "Separe a resposta com vírgulas. Ex: 'X, Y' (X é o número maior, Y é o número menor)",
    "percent": false,
    "credit": "RachaCuca",
    "creditlink": "http://rachacuca.com.br",
    "name": "Hidden Numbers",
    "name_pt": "Números Ocultos",
    "next": "PUZZLE/5"
  },
  "5": {
    "question": "If \"one and a half boy\" can eat one and a half hot dog in one and a half minute, how many hot dogs can 6 boys eat in 6 minutes?",
    "question_pt": "Se \"um garoto e meio\" consegue comer um cachorro quente e meio em um minuto e meio, quantos cachorros quentes 6 garotos conseguem comer em 6 minutos?",
    "answer": "24",
    "answer_pt": "24",
    "note": "Numeric digits only. E.g: '10' if you want to say 10 hot dogs.",
    "note_pt": "Números somente. Ex: '10' se você quiser dizer 10 cachorros quentes.",
    "percent": false,
    "credit": "RachaCuca",
    "creditlink": "http://rachacuca.com.br",
    "name": "Hot Dogs",
    "name_pt": "Cachorros Quentes",
    "next": "PUZZLE/6"
  },
  "6": {
    "question": "37.2350° N, 115.8111° W",
    "question_pt": "37.2350° N, 115.8111° W",
    "answer": "Area 51",
    "answer_pt": "Area 51",
    "note": "7 letters (space is a letter)",
    "note_pt": "7 letras (espaço é uma letra)",
    "percent": false,
    "credit": false,
    "next": "PUZZLE/7"
  },
  "7": {
    "question": "In a certain country 1/2 of 5 = 3. Assuming the same proportion, what would be the value of 1/3 of 10 ?",
    "question_pt": "Em um determinado país, 1/2 de 5 = 3. Assumindo a mesma proproção, qual seria o valor de 1/3 de 10?",
    "answer": "4",
    "answer_pt": "4",
    "note": "Please answer using numeric digits.",
    "note_pt": "Responda usando números (dígitos).",
    "percent": false,
    "credit": "Buzzle.com",
    "creditlink": "http://www.buzzle.com/",
    "name": "Proportions",
    "name_pt": "Proporções",
    "next": "PUZZLE/8"
  },
  "8": {
    "question": "072 097 099 107 101 114 032 069 120 112 101 114 105 101 110 099 101",
    "question_pt": "072 097 099 107 101 114 032 069 120 112 101 114 105 101 110 099 101",
    "answer": "Hacker Experience",
    "answer_pt": "Hacker Experience",
    "note": "It<a href=\"http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ASCII\">'</a>s actually easy.",
    "note_pt": "Não é tão difícil assim.<a href=\"http://pt.wikipedia.org/wiki/ASCII\">.</a>.",
    "percent": false,
    "credit": false,
    "next": "PUZZLE/9"
  },
  "9": {
    "question": "Setec Astronomy",
    "question_pt": "Setec Astronomy",
    "answer": "Too Many Secrets",
    "answer_pt": "Too Many Secrets",
    "note": "<a href=\"http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0105435/\">Sneakers</a>.",
    "note_pt": "<a href=\"http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0105435/\">Sneakers</a>.",
    "percent": false,
    "credit": false,
    "next": "PUZZLE/10"
  },
  "10": {
    "path": "sudoku",
    "credit": "derletztekick.com",
    "creditlink": "http://sourceforge.net/projects/sudoku-puzzle/",
    "next": "WHOIS/1",
    "name": "Sudoku",
    "name_pt": "Sudoku"
  },
  "WHOIS1": {
    "path": "2048",
    "credit": "Forkk.net",
    "creditlink": "http://www.forkk.net",
    "next": "WHOIS/2",
    "name": "2048",
    "name_pt": "2048"
  },
  "11": {
    "question": "01010011 01110100 01100001 01111001 01001000 01110101 01101110 01100111 01110010 01111001 00101100<br/> 01010011 01110100 01100001 01111001 01000110 01101111 01101111 01101100 01101001 01110011 01101000",
    "question_pt": "01010011 01110100 01100001 01111001 01001000 01110101 01101110 01100111 01110010 01111001 00101100<br/> 01010011 01110100 01100001 01111001 01000110 01101111 01101111 01101100 01101001 01110011 01101000",
    "answer": "Stay Hungry, Stay Foolish",
    "answer_pt": "Stay Hungry, Stay Foolish",
    "percent": false,
    "credit": false,
    "next": "PUZZLE/12"
  },
  "12": {    
    "question": "In Alexander Dumas' book, \"The Three Musketeers\", two of the musketeers are called Athos and Porthos. What was the name of the third Musketeer?",
    "question_pt": "No livro de Alexander Dumas, \"Os Três Mosqueteiros\", dois dos mosqueteiros se chamam Athos e Porthos. Qual era o nome do terceiro Mosqueteiro?",
    "answer": "Aramis",
    "answer_pt": "Aramis",
    "percent": false,
    "credit": false,
    "next": "PUZZLE/13"
  },
  "13": {
    "question": "One boy can eat 100 chocolate bars in half a minute (!). The other buy eats half of this amount on the double of the time. How many chocolate bars can both eat, together, in 15 seconds?",
    "question_pt": "Um garoto consegue comer 100 barras de chocolate e meio minuto. Um outro garoto consegue comer a metade dessa quantidade gastando o dobro desse tempo. Quantas barras de chocolate os dois garotos, juntos, conseguem comer em 15 segundos?",
    "answer": "62.5",
    "answer_pt": "62.5",
    "note": "Use point (dot?) if it's not an integer. (e.g: '1.5' if they can eat one and half bar)",
    "note_pt": "Use ponto se não for um número inteiro. (Ex: '1.5' se eles comem 1 barra e meia)",
    "percent": false,
    "credit": "RachaCuca",
    "creditlink": "http://rachacuca.com.br",
    "name": "Fat Boys",
    "name_pt": "Barras de Chocolate",
    "next": "PUZZLE/14"
  },
  "14": {
    "question": "Potatos are made 99% of water and only 1% of \"potato stuff\". Maddog bought 100 kilograms of potato and left them outside his home, taking a \"sun bath\". When he was back, he noticed the potatoes had been dried and had, now, only 98% of water in their composition. At that moment, what was the new weight of the potatoes?",
    "question_pt": "As batatas possuem, em sua constituição, 99% de água e apenas 1% de \"material de batata\", propriamente dito. João comprou 100 kg de batatas e as deixou no quintal, tomando um \"banho de sol\". Quando ele voltou, viu que as batatas haviam desidratado e possuíam, agora, apenas 98 % de água em sua composição. Naquele momento, qual era o novo peso das batatas?",
    "answer": "50",
    "answer_pt": "50",
    "note": "Numeric digits only, do not put kilograms. E.g: '10' if you want to say 10 kilograms.",
    "note_pt": "Números somente, não coloque kg. Ex: '10' se você quiser dizer 10 kg.",
    "percent": false,
    "credit": "RachaCuca",
    "creditlink": "http://rachacuca.com.br",
    "name": "Dried Potatoes",
    "name_pt": "Batatas Malucas",
    "next": "PUZZLE/15"
  },
  "15": {
    "question": "A farmer went to your bank to ask for a loan. The bank agreed on offering $100 as long as the farmer would be able to buy exactly 100 animals with those $100.<br/><br/>The only rule of the agreement was that the farmer would buy at least one of each of the following animals: ox, pigs and sheeps. Each ox costs $10. Each pigs costs $3, and the sheeps costs, each, $0.50. How many animals of each kind did the farmer buy?",
    "question_pt": "Um fazendeiro foi ao encontro de seu gerente de banco pedir um empréstimo para comprar animais. O gerente fez um acordo com o ele. Ele disse que emprestaria R$ 100,00 e que o fazendeiro não precisaria devolver o dinheiro ao banco caso conseguisse comprar exatamente 100 cabeças (animais) com os R$ 100,00.<br/><br/>A única regra do acordo era que o fazendeiro comprasse pelo menos um animal de cada um desses tipos: bois, porcos e ovelhas. Cada boi custa R$ 10,00. Cada porco custa R$ 3,00 e as ovelhas custam, cada uma, R$ 0,50. Quantos animais de cada tipo o fazendeiro comprou?",
    "answer": "5, 1, 94",
    "answer_pt": "5, 1, 94",
    "note": "Separate the answer using commas. E.g.: 'X, Y, Z' (X ox, Y pigs and Z sheeps)",
    "note_pt": "Separe a resposta com vírgulas. Ex: 'X, Y, Z' (X bois, Y porcos e Z ovelhas)",
    "percent": false,
    "credit": "RachaCuca",
    "creditlink": "http://rachacuca.com.br",
    "name": "Crazy Banker",
    "name_pt": "Banqueiro maluco",
    "next": "PUZZLE/16"
  },
  "16": {
    "path": "minesweeper",
    "credit": "Uzi Kilon",
    "creditlink": "http://kilon.org/blog/",
    "next": "PUZZLE\\3",
    "name": "Minesweeper",
    "name_pt": "Campo minado",
    "next": "PUZZLE/17"
  },
  "17": {
    "question": "Renato and Matheus told, enthusiastically, the result of the Third International Science Fair, which took place in Switzerland. There were 3 competitors: Naomy, Milena and Phoebe. Renato told Naomy was the winner, with Milena getting the second place. Matheus, however,  said Phoebe won, and Naomy was second placed..<br/><br/>Actually none of them told the truth about what happened at the Science Fair. What really happened was that each one told one true statement and a false one. So, what was the actual classification of the competitors?",
    "question_pt": "Renato e Matheus contavam, muito empolgados, o resultado da Terceira Feira Anual Internacional de Ciências, realizada na Suécia. Na feira, havia 3 competidores: Naomy, Milena e Phoebe. Renato disse que Naomy havia sido o vencedor, com Milena ficando em segundo lugar. Já Matheus, disse que Phoebe ganhou, com Naomy em segundo.<br/><br/>Na verdade, nenhum dos dois contou inteiramente a verdade sobre os resultados da feira de ciências. O que ocorreu foi que cada um deu uma afirmação verdadeira e outra falsa sobre a classificação. Diga: Qual foi a verdadeira classificação dos competidores?",
    "answer": "Phoebe, Milena, Naomy",
    "answer_pt": "Phoebe, Milena, Naomy",
    "note": "Answer using the name of the first, second and third placed, respectively. Example: Melchior, Gaspar, Baltazar",
    "note_pt": "Responda usando o nome do primeiro, segundo e terceiro colocado, respectivamente. Exemplo: Melchior, Gaspar, Baltazar",
    "percent": false,
    "credit": "RachaCuca",
    "creditlink": "http://rachacuca.com.br",
    "next": "PUZZLE/18",
    "name": "Little Liars",
    "name_pt": "Competidores mentirosos"
  },
  "18": {
    "question": "You are the onwer of a bird store, and you use them to organize your cages. If you keep 1 bird per cage, there will be one bird outside of the cage, therefore it will be missing cages. If you keep two birds per cage, there will be one empty cage. How many birds and cages do you have?",
    "question_pt": "Você é o dono de uma loja de animais e tem canários para organizar nas gaiolas. Se você colocar 1 canário por gaiola, restará um canário fora da gaiola, ou seja, faltarão gaiolas. Se você colocar 2 canários por gaiola, sobrará uma gaiola vazia. Quantos canários e quantas gaiolas você tem?",
    "answer": "4, 3",
    "answer_pt": "4, 3",
    "note": "Separate the answer using commas. E.g.: 'X, Y' (X birds, Y cages)",
    "note_pt": "Separe a resposta com vírgulas. Ex: 'X, Y' (X canários, Y gaiolas)",
    "percent": false,
    "credit": "RachaCuca",
    "creditlink": "http://rachacuca.com.br",
    "name": "Birds And Cages",
    "name_pt": "Canários e Gaiolas",
    "next": "PUZZLE/19"
  },
  "19": {
    "question": "Five competitors (A, B, C, D e E) dispute a swimming test that rewards the 1st, 2nd and 3rd placed with gold, silver and bronze medal, respectively. The following assertments about the test are fake, but one assertment of each (note each have two assertments) can be true.<ul><li>A did not get gold and B did not get silver;</li><li>D did not get silver and B did not get bronze;</li><li>C won a medal, but D didn't;</li><li>A won a medal, but C didn't;</li><li>D won a medal and E did, too.</li></ul>",
    "question_pt": "Cinco competidores (A, B, C, D e E) disputam uma prova de natação que premia o 1º, 2º e 3º colocados com medalhas de ouro, prata e bronze, respectivamente. As seguintes conclusões sobre a prova são falsas, mas uma afirmação de cada uma delas (note que cada conclusão possui duas afirmações) pode ser verdadeira.<ul><li>A não ganhou o ouro e B não ganhou a prata;</li><li>D não ganhou a prata e B não ganhou o bronze;</li><li>C ganhou uma medalha, já D não ganhou nenhuma;</li><li>A ganhou uma medalha, já C não ganhou nenhuma;</li><li>D ganhou uma medalha e E também.</li></ul>",
    "answer": "a, d, c",
    "answer_pt": "A, D, C",
    "note": "Answer using the letter of the first, second and third placed, respectively. Example: X, Y, Z",
    "note_pt": "Responda usando a letra do primeiro, segundo e terceiro colocado, respectivamente. Exemplo: X, Y, Z",
    "percent": false,
    "credit": "RachaCuca",
    "creditlink": "http://rachacuca.com.br",
    "next": "PUZZLE/20",
    "name": "Swimmers",
    "name_pt": "Medalhistas da natação"
  },
  "20": {
    "question": "A whale have 15 meters of length. Her head is as big as her tail. If her head was two times longer than it actually is, her head and her tail, together, would be as long as the rest of her body (i.e., the part that is between the head and the tail). What is the length of her head, tail and the rest of the body?",
    "question_pt": "Uma baleia tem 15 metros de comprimento. Sua cabeça é tão grande quanto sua cauda. Se a cabeça fosse duas vezes mais comprida do que realmente é, a cauda e a cabeça, juntas, seriam tão compridas quanto o resto do corpo da baleia (ou seja, a parte que está entre a cauda e a cabeça). Qual é o comprimento da cabeça, cauda e o restante do corpo?",
    "answer": "3, 3, 9",
    "answer_pt": "3, 3, 9",
    "note": "Separate the answer using commas. E.g.: 'X, Y, Z' (X meters for head, Y meters for tail and Z meters for the body)",
    "note_pt": "Separe a resposta com vírgulas. Ex: 'X, Y, Z' (X metros pra cabeça, Y metros pra cauda e Z metros pro restante do corpo)",
    "percent": false,
    "credit": "RachaCuca",
    "creditlink": "http://rachacuca.com.br",
    "name": "The Whale",
    "name_pt": "A Baleia",
    "next": "PUZZLE/21"
  },
  "21": {
    "question": "Brent, Corrigan and Bieber went out to birdwatching. Each one saw a bird that no one else did. Each pair between them saw a bird that the third didn't. Finally, one bird was seen by everyone. From the birds Brent saw, 2 were yellow. From the birds Corrigan saw, 3 were yellow. From the birds Bieber saw, 4 were yellow.<br/><br/>How many yellow birds were seen altogether?<br/>How many birds with other colors were seen altogether?",
    "question_pt": "Brent, Corrigan e Bieber saíram para observar pássaros. Cada um viu um pássaro que nenhum dos outros viu. Cada par formado entre eles viu um pássaro que o terceiro não viu. Por fim, um pássaro foi visto por todos. Dos pássaros que Brent viu, 2 eram amarelos. Dos pássaros que Corrigan viu, 3 eram amarelos. Dos pássaros que Bieber viu, 4 eram amarelos.<br/><br/>Quantos pássaros amarelos foram vistos ao todo?<br/>Quantos pássaros de outras cores foram visto ao todo?",
    "answer": "5, 2",
    "answer_pt": "5, 2",
    "note": "Answer the questions separated by a comma. Example: 3, 4",
    "note_pt": "Responda as perguntadas separando por vírgula. Exemplo: 3, 4",
    "percent": false,
    "credit": "RachaCuca",
    "creditlink": "http://rachacuca.com.br",
    "next": "PUZZLE/22",
    "name": "Birdwatching",
    "name_pt": "Observando pássaros"
  },
  "22": {
    "question": "How could you display the number 100 using only six times the number \"9\", without any other digit, and with only two operations?",
    "question_pt": "Como você poderia expressar o número 100 usando apenas seis vezes o algarismo “9”, sem nenhum outro dígito, e com somente duas operações?",
    "answer": "99+99/99",
    "answer_pt": "99+99/99",
    "note": "You might need to use fractions. Do not insert spaces in the answer. (e.g.: 5+3*2)",
    "note_pt": "Você pode usar frações. Não coloque espaços na resposta. (Ex: 5+3*2)",
    "percent": false,
    "credit": "RachaCuca",
    "creditlink": "http://rachacuca.com.br",
    "name": "Number 100",
    "name_pt": "Número 100",
    "next": "PUZZLE/23"
  },
  "23": {
    "question": "Two crocodile owners (owner I and owner II) were talking and, during the conversation, they realised a weird coincidence. If owner I sold 7 of his crocodile to owner II, owner I would have the same amount of crocodiles as owner II. On the other side, if owner II sold 7 of his crocodiles to owner I, owner I would have exactly the double of crocodiles of owner II. How many crocodiles each of them have?",
    "question_pt": "Dois criadores de jacarés (criador I e criador II) estavam conversando, e, durante o curso da conversa, eles notaram uma curiosa coincidência. Se o criador I vendesse 7 jacarés ao criador II, o criador I ficaria com o mesmo número de jacarés que o criador II. Por outro lado, se o criador II vendesse ao criador I 7 jacarés, o criador I ficaria exatamente com o dobro do número de jacarés do criador II. Quantos jacarés cada um deles possui?",
    "answer": "49, 35",
    "answer_pt": "49, 35",
    "note": "Separate the answer using commas. E.g.: 'X, Y' (X crocodiles for owner I, Y crocodiles for owner II)",
    "note_pt": "Separe a resposta com vírgulas. Ex: 'X, Y' (X jacarés do criador I, Y jacarés do criador II)",
    "percent": false,
    "credit": "RachaCuca",
    "creditlink": "http://rachacuca.com.br",
    "name": "Crocodiles",
    "name_pt": "Criadores de Jacarés",
    "next": "PUZZLE/24"
  },
  "24": {
    "question": "∀x Player(x) ^ (∃y,z Premium(y) ^ Buys(x, y, z)) => Awesome(x)",
    "question_pt": "∀x Jogador(x) ^ (∃y,z Premium(y) ^ Compra(x, y, z)) => Lindo(x)",
    "answer": "Every player who buys premium is awesome",
    "answer_pt": "Todo jogador que compra premium é lindo",
    "note": "You need to match at least 90% of the correct answer. <a href=\"http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First-order_logic\">Good</a> <a href=\"http://feature-space.com/en/document41.pdf\">luck</a>.",
    "note_pt": "Você precisa acertar pelo menos 90% da resposta original. <a href=\"http://pt.wikipedia.org/wiki/L%C3%B3gica_de_primeira_ordem\">Boa</a> <a href=\"https://fenix.tecnico.ulisboa.pt/downloadFile/3779572136691/cap8-lpo-2008.pdf\">sorte</a>.",
    "percent": 90,
    "credit": false,
    "next": "PUZZLE/25"
  },
  "25": {
    "question": "A group of sheeps and chickens have a total of 99 feet and heads (counting together, i.e. it's *wrong* to say there are 99 feet and 99 heads, we only now the total amount of feet + heads). There are two times more chickens than sheeps. How many animals of each type (sheeps and chickens) are there in this group?",
    "question_pt": "Um grupo que reúne ovelhas e galinha, tem um total de 99 pés e cabeças (contando juntamente, ou seja, não é correto dizer que existem 99 pés e 99 cabeças, pois só se sabe o total, e não o valor de cada um em separado). Há duas vezes mais galinhas que ovelhas. Quantos animais de cada (ovelhas e galinhas) existem nesse grupo?",
    "answer": "9, 18",
    "answer_pt": "9, 18",
    "note": "Separate the answer using commas. E.g.: 'X, Y' (X sheeps, Y chickens)",
    "note_pt": "Separe a resposta com vírgulas. Ex: 'X, Y' (X ovelhas, Y galinhas)",
    "percent": false,
    "credit": "RachaCuca",
    "creditlink": "http://rachacuca.com.br",
    "name": "Sheeps and Chickens",
    "name_pt": "Ovelhas e Galinhas",
    "next": "PUZZLE/26"
  },
  "26": {
    "question": "/bb|[^b]{2}/",
    "question_pt": "/bb|[^b]{2}/",
    "answer": "To be or not to be",
    "answer_pt": "To be or not to be",
    "note": "<a href=\"https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regular_expression\">Regular Expression</a>.",
    "note_pt": "<a href=\"https://pt.wikipedia.org/wiki/Express%C3%A3o_regular\">Expressão Regular</a>.",
    "percent": 90,
    "credit": false,
    "next": "PUZZLE/27"
  },
  "27": {
    "path": "lightsout",
    "credit": "chenglou",
    "creditlink": "https://github.com/chenglou/react-lights-out",
    "next": "PUZZLE/28",
    "name": "Lights Out",
    "name_pt": "Lights Out"
  },
  "28": {
    "path": "lightsout",
    "credit": "chenglou",
    "creditlink": "https://github.com/chenglou/react-lights-out",
    "next": "WHOIS/2",
    "name": "Lights Out",
    "name_pt": "Lights Out"
  },
  "WHOIS2": {
    "path": "lightsout",
    "credit": "chenglou",
    "creditlink": "https://github.com/chenglou/react-lights-out",
    "next": "TMPEND",
    "name": "Lights Out",
    "name_pt": "Lights Out"
  }
}
